The Twin is a thriller, drama, tv movie film directed by Fred Olen Ray.
Jocelyn's boyfriend is perfect--except for his dangerous identical twin
brother, Derek, who just escaped from a mental institution.
When Derek unspools a twisted plan of revenge with Jocelyn in his crosshairs, her
mother Ashley must act fast before she falls victim to a psychopath.
Ashley, played by Brigid Brannagh.
Derek / Tyler, played by Timothy Granaderos.
Jocelyn Rose, played by Jess Gabor.
Dr. Rubin, played by Mark Lindsay Chapman.
Jeke, played by Louis Mandylor.
Sherri, played by Calista Carradine.
The third season of the surrealist mystery-horror drama television series Twin Peaks, billed as Twin Peaks: The Return
and Twin Peaks: A Limited Event Series, premiered on May 21, 2017, and concluded on September 3, 2017.
The 18-episode season was broadcast in the United States on Showtime.
It marked the Twin Peaks franchise's return to television after an absence of over 25 years, and continued storylines from the first
two seasons (1990–1991) and their part-prequel, part-sequel theatrical film, Twin Peaks: Fire Walk with Me (1992).
The show's co-creators David Lynch and Mark Frost returned to write
the third season, with Lynch directing every episode.
Set 25 years after the events of the original Twin Peaks, the season follows multiple storylines, most of which are linked to FBI agent
Dale Cooper (Kyle MacLachlan) and his 1989 investigation into the murder of high school student Laura Palmer (Sheryl Lee).
In addition to the fictional Washington state town of Twin Peaks, the story extends to
locations such as New York City, Las Vegas, South Dakota, New Mexico, and Texas.
Showtime president David Nevins said the story's central
focus was "Cooper's odyssey back to Twin Peaks".
The series garnered critical acclaim, with praise for its unconventional
narrative structure, visual invention, and performances.
Critics have hailed the show as the best television show of 2017 and the
2010s, as well as one of the best shows of the 21st century.
Some critics also consider The Return a film, with film journal Cahiers du Cinéma naming it the best film of the
decade and the 2022 Sight & Sound critics' poll voting it the 152nd-greatest film in history.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.